Matthias Müringer

Full-Stack Web Developer

	https://matthiasmueringer.de	0	github.com/koola123
L	+49 (0) 176 744 27 691	in	linkedin.com/in/matthiasmueringer
ightharpoons	mmueringer@web.de	\mathbf{y}	@MatthiasMueringer
9	Wiesbaden, Germany		

I'm a certified web developer with strong creative, analytical skills, and an eye-for-detail in building customized web pages. I possess business acumen and experience working in multicultural and cross-border teams, and bring especially skills in selling products and services that require explanation and perseverance. My strong analytical and goal-oriented approach make me a good fit for any kind of team in the development process of innovative solutions.

MAJOR WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

MyFlix App https://myflix-movies-client.netlify.app/

A full-fledged full-stack web application. On the frontend with a beautiful responsive webpage with routing, rich interactions, several interface views, and a polished user experience. It was created with React and Redux for state management. On the backend a REST API will provide users with access to information about different movies, directors and genres. Users will be able to sign up, update their personal information, and create a list of their favorite movies. It was created with Node.js, Express and using modern API structure. A MongoDB database was created to store all the data.

Meet App https://koola123.github.io/meet/

It shows upcoming full-stack meetups around the world. A serverless, progressive web application (PWA) with React using a test-driven development (TDD) technique. The application uses the Google Calendar API and Serverless functions (AWS lambda) for the authorization server instead of using a traditional server to fetch the events.

CODING & PROGRAMMING EXPERIENCES

IT Bootcamp graduate

• Completed CareerFoundry's Full-Stack Web Development program.

• Designed and deployed several web applications on GitHub.

Technical JavaScript, React, Redux Node.js/Express.js

TypeScript, Angular

React Native

SKILLS

HTML5/CSS3/SASS

Bootstrap

MongoDB, SQL

Git, GitHub

Test Driven Development
Progressive Web Applications

AWS Lambda Functions

PROFESSIONAL

Team player

Very creative
Strong problem solver

Technology savvy

PREVIOUS WORK EXPERIENCES

Key Account Manager & Senior Sales Manager

Yourfirm | February 2022 - February 2023

- Selling job advertisements and recruiting products to SMEs in Germany.
- Creating sales reports and forecast planning for the following months.

Sales Consultant

Monster Worldwide | January 2020 - December 2020

 \bullet B-2-B Sales of job advertisement and recruiting solutions to SMEs in Germany.

Account Manager Telesales CH New Business

Monster Worldwide | June 2019 - December 2019

• B-2-B Selling job advertisements and recruiting solutions to the Swiss market.

Consultant IT & Technology

Robert Half | October 2018 - February 2019

CareerFoundry | April 2021 - May 2023

- Recruitment of IT-specialists, conducting interviews and placing candidates to companies.
- Active Sourcing of IT experts via Xing, Linkedin and Social Media. Attending job fairs to get in contact with new talents.
- Negotiating contracts with potential B-2-B customers, and building long term relationships in the IT sector.

Account Manager North & East Germany

Hertz Corporation | February 2013 - September 2018

- New customer acquisition and existing customer care to SMEs.
- Definition of requirements and preparation of quotations and tenders based on the rental needs of companies.
- Selling short- and long-term rentals like Hertz Minilease (a competitive long-term rental option for private customers).
- Competitor monitoring (Sixt, Europear, Avis, Enterprise) on the German car rental and fleet market and derivation of recommendations for actions in consultation with the Key Account Manager and Head of Telesales.
- Monthly reporting of sales volume for new contracts and definition of new KPIs.

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Web Development CareerFoundry, Berlin (Germany) 2021 - 2023

B.A. in Business AdministrationSouth Westphalia University of AppliedSciences, Meschede (Germany)2014 - 2015

Master of Business Administration (VWA) VWA, Wiesbaden (Germany)

2008 - 201

BRITA SE

Industrial Management Assistant Taunusstein (Germany)

2004 - 2006

LANGUAGES

English (Professional) German (Native)